<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove.atom"/>
  <title>NicheCanvas - Art Love</title>
  <updated>2020-06-29T02:52:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>NicheCanvas</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/simple-budget-friendly-redecorating-tips-with-major-impact</id>
    <published>2020-06-29T02:52:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-03T12:53:25-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/simple-budget-friendly-redecorating-tips-with-major-impact"/>
    <title>Simple Budget Friendly Redecorating Tips with Major Impact</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>There are a million and one ways to redecorate your home. How and what you do really depends on a few things: your space, your design preferences, and your budget.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/simple-budget-friendly-redecorating-tips-with-major-impact">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/1_fb76de2a-70a8-4816-9980-3dd62791fd65_2048x2048.jpg?v=1593260852" alt=""></p>
<p>There are a million and one ways to redecorate your home. How and what you do really depends on a few things: your space, your design preferences, and your budget.</p>
<p>Now we can’t do much to change the space you’re in. If you’re up for a demo and construction project, you’re on your own.</p>
<p>But we can help with making some easy decorating tips for minimal cost and maximum effect. Here is our pick for easy DIY projects you can do this weekend.</p>
<h1>Jazz up a bland wall.</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;">If you’ve got a boring wall, (and believe us, you know if your walls are boring), get some inexpensive frames in all black or white and hang them up in a grid formation. Fill the frames with B&amp;W prints from your local print kiosk for an affordable but elegant look.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;">When in doubt, hang something. Like a shelf.</h1>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog2_7dd47745-27d5-4df2-9497-3f4a519c2b35_2048x2048.jpg?v=1593412394" alt=""></p>
<p>Shelves can do wondrous things in a room. There’s the obvious perk of being able to put stuff on them. But depending on your room, you can add some perceived square footage to the naked eye.</p>
<p>A long shelf can make a narrow room appear wider. And if you’re really bold, hang it near the ceiling and it will have the affect of drawing the eye up. Maximum storage and beautifying your space at the same time? Yes, thank you!</p>
<h1></h1>
<h1>Accent a wall.</h1>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog2_f1e54445-fe45-43f9-bff0-cf23e76cac16_2048x2048.jpg?v=1593795091" alt=""></p>
<p>Painting can be… well, a pain. But the effort it takes to paint a single accent wall is significantly less and you can still reap most of the benefits of a newly updated room. Have fun with color choice or try a bold pattern like stripes. The ceiling’s the limit!</p>
<h1>Mirror, mirror on the wall.</h1>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog3_43aa334b-b71d-4ddb-91f5-946439f6f2e5_2048x2048.jpg?v=1593795163" alt=""></p>
<p>Bring in light. Create the illusion of more space. Reflect something cool from another wall. Whatever you’re looking for, mirrors are pretty awesome and usually up for the task. Plus, we know you’ll appreciate the ability to check yourself out once in a while.</p>
<p>Hang them. Prop them. Lean them. Play with size and have fun with frames (or not). The best part is they are easy to find at thrift stores so you won’t stress your budget.</p>
<h1>Give your doors a dose of drama.</h1>
<p>Who says your doors have to match your trim? Go crazy. Paint ‘em black and keep the trim white. It's a bold look but will definitely add some pizazz to your home.</p>
<p>Still not convinced? Google it to see just how cool it'll look. Go ahead. You know you want to.</p>
<h1>Move your artwork.</h1>
<p>Maybe the key to your room refresh is simply moving around the artwork already in your home. Swap some things around. Put art in unexpected places. Sometimes a new wall is all your artwork needs to look fresh and new.</p>
<h1>Add some greenery.</h1>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/1a_1c21bd0d-9531-421e-bede-ad5239028662_2048x2048.jpg?v=1593690696" alt=""></p>
<p>Plants can be the breath of fresh air a room needs. Literally. They freshen the air. Thrift around for some antique ceramics to use as planters or slap a new coat of paint on an old terracotta pot you have lying around.</p>
<p>Don’t have a green thumb? Succulents are pretty hardy and don’t require much daily maintenance. Place a few in colorful pots around a room for a pop of vibrant color.</p>
<p>There are many creative ways to spruce up your space without breaking the bank. And the best part is you don't need a ton of time or a hefty budget to make big changes. So get inspired and try out some of these ideas in your own home.</p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/New_NC_2048x2048_a78994de-a65d-4b82-a803-d42b7ae6f173_2048x2048.jpg?v=1593408738" style="float: left;"></a><br><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/ButtonNew_2048x2048_2537c8c0-4ec7-4429-901b-ef6831b5e841_2048x2048.jpg?v=1593408753" style="float: left;"></a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/your-questions-about-mats-answered</id>
    <published>2020-06-11T03:53:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-22T04:49:51-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/your-questions-about-mats-answered"/>
    <title>Fall In Love With Your Framed Art - Again!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div>You’ve found the perfect piece of art, and chose the ideal frame. You put the two together, but it just doesn’t seem right.</div>
<div>
<br>Could it be you need to mat your artwork? Perhaps.<span> </span>
</div><p><a class="read-more" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/your-questions-about-mats-answered">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Blog1_8749b5fd-da26-4ba4-ae7b-302749205a77_2048x2048.jpg?v=1591810159" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Once upon a time, you found the perfect piece of art, and chose the ideal frame. You put the two together, hung it on the wall, and loved how it looked.</p>
<p>But over time, the passion cooled.</p>
<p>You don't need an <em>"art counselor"</em> to take your relationship back to <em>"love"</em> from <em>"like."</em></p>
<p>All you need is a mat.</p>
<p>Adding a mat elevates the look of your piece of art. It adds style and sophistication and takes your art from <em>“meh”</em> to <em>“marvelous.”</em></p>
<p>Ready to fall head over heels for your art again?</p>
<div><em></em></div>
<div><em></em></div>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Let’s explore mats</strong></h1>
<p><strong><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog2_14664b8b-ba87-4184-84d9-0fac70ff6acd_2048x2048.jpg?v=1591811293" alt=""></strong></p>
<p>In the picture framing industry, a mat (or matte) is a thin, flat piece of paper-based material included within a picture frame.</p>
<p>Mats usually serve one of two purposes. They’re additional decoration to make your art pop, or they’re used to keep the artwork from touching the glass frame.</p>
<p>From a practical perspective, mats are essential because they protect the artwork.</p>
<p>Placing a mat between your artwork and the framing glass prevents any condensation that might develop on the inside of the glass from transferring to your art and causing water damage, mold, or mildew.</p>
<p>But practicality aside, mats are pretty. Matting artwork intensifies it by adding size, color, and depth.</p>
<h1>How to choose a mat</h1>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog5_0bf64455-6e03-4ce1-bfa8-7149b808f940_2048x2048.jpg?v=1591979277" alt=""></p>
<p>From a classic point-of-view, most professionals believe the mat should be lighter than the art or picture but darker than the wall where it’s hung.</p>
<p>In these cases, most mats are neutral colors such as gray, white, and cream.<br>And, experts say the mat border should be 2 times the width of the frame.</p>
<p>If you want your wall gallery to have a museum-type feel, this is a great choice.</p>
<p>But what if you don’t? This is where the fun begins!</p>
<h1>Small-ish art</h1>
<p>If your artwork is small, a mat gives tiny masterpieces the wall space they deserve. And here’s where the <em>“2 times rule”</em> about the width of the mat and the frame is forgotten.</p>
<h1>Interesting border</h1>
<p>Does your artwork have an attractive border? If it’s a painting on handmade paper, the edge is as impressive as the art.</p>
<p>In this case, you want a floating frame. Your art is mounted on an acid-free foam core lift, hidden behind the work, but attached to a supporting mat. A spacer ensures the surface of the work doesn’t touch the glass.</p>
<p>Floating frames are the way to go if your piece has a printed border, or if your piece is signed near the edge.</p>
<h1><strong>Photographs</strong></h1>
<p><strong><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog5_389575e3-3b4a-40c3-8a1c-6a30a70e00c6_2048x2048.jpg?v=1591860539" alt=""></strong></p>
<p>If you’re framing a photograph, a mat can make it pop, especially if your photo is black and white. A crisp white mat can elevate the appearance.</p>
<p>Now that we’ve explored appropriate mats for different types of art, let’s talk about specific types of mats.</p>
<h1>Multiples</h1>
<p>A mat can have several openings. This is a great way to show off newspaper or magazine articles or to include several smaller photos in one frame. </p>
<h1>Colored mats</h1>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog6_2048x2048.jpg?v=1591861892" alt=""></p>
<p>Use colored mats to pick-up a particular shade in your artwork. But be aware that using a colored mat may limit where you can place the piece, as it might not look good in every room.</p>
<p>For this reason, some professionals don’t use colored mats but opt for a white or black mat.</p>
<h1>Single mat, double mat</h1>
<p>A single mat is just that. One mat, in one color, surrounding the artwork.</p>
<p>A double mat is 2 layered mats. Approximately one-quarter of an inch of the lower mat peeks out, creating a different color border around the art.</p>
<p>If you want to add a second color without a double-matting, some mats are colored on the surface, but have a white interior that is revealed with the mat is cut, which can add interest, too.</p>
<h1>Custom mat, custom frame</h1>
<p>A mat will add to the final dimensions of your finished piece. If your artwork 11x14”, once you add a mat, it could be around 17x20” or larger. Therefore, be aware you might need a custom-size frame to accommodate your matted artwork if it’s not a standard size.</p>
<h1>Let’s mat</h1>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog4_d3de1ede-b0b7-4dde-8cae-5eb4b7b3465b_2048x2048.jpg?v=1591979151" alt=""></p>
<p>To reignite your love for your art, play the field, so to speak. Experiment with different mat colors, sizes, and combinations. Let your imagination run wild.</p>
<p>You're sure to fall in love with your art again. </p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/New_NC_983e5b4f-a24a-4954-a12a-d041ef1252d6_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590589836" style="float: left;"></a><br><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/ButtonNew_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590586838" style="float: left;"></a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/a-new-decade-means-new-home-design-trends</id>
    <published>2020-05-22T09:11:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-28T01:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/a-new-decade-means-new-home-design-trends"/>
    <title>A New Decade Means New Home Design Trends.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/image1_facf7012-a348-4f87-8174-903fe63ea056_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590140269" style="float: none;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">Buh-bye white kitchens. Farewell, fiddle fig trees. Let’s take a look at what</div>
<div style="text-align: left;">designers have in store for our homes for 2020.</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Navy Blue</strong></h1>
<div style="text-align: left;">The 2020 Pantone Color of the Year is Classic Blue. This navy shade works anywhere, from dramatic wall paint accented with white trim, to a colorful, yet subtle kitchen island. Navy is versatile and sophisticated, so that you can use it anywhere. </div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<h1 style="text-align: left;">Floral Wallpaper</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/floral_wall_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590590478" alt=""></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Don’t flinch. Gone are the rigid rows and cookie-cutter patterns. This season’s floral wallpapers feature large scale, bold colors, non-repeating patterns, and even metallic colors. Paper the powder room or foyer for a welcoming pop of pow.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;">Non-White Kitchens</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;">The defining trend of the 2010s, all-white kitchens were bland and boring. There’s a shift to bringing in natural wood in cabinetry, shelving, and islands, which keeps a light and airy vibe without overkill.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;">Colorful Kitchen Cabinets</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/nc5_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590143088" style="float: none;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">A definite 180° from the all-white kitchen, colored cabinets are in. Unconventional colors such as dark red, bright yellow, forest green, or navy blue add an unexpected pop to base cabinets, upper cabinets, or islands.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;">Canopy Beds</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/nc_6_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590146078" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Release your inner princess! No longer funky and clunky, or frilly and fussy, canopy beds with frames of acrylic or metal, and sleek fabrics are what’s happening in the bedroom.</p>
<h1>Olive Trees</h1>
<p>If 2019 was the year of the dramatic fiddle leaf fig, then 2020 is the year of the much subtler olive tree. Instead of blooming bright green, these trees are a more sophisticated sage.</p>
<h1>Antique Art</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blogs2_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590643489" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Vintage is in for 2020, especially in art. Aged frames paired with paintings that tell a story look great anywhere.</p>
<h1>Kitchen Art</h1>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog5_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590593303" alt=""></p>
<p>No, we didn’t say kitchen kitsch. This year, people are genuinely making the kitchen a room in the house and not just a place to cook. Look for interesting pieces on the wall or personal items displayed on shelves. </p>
<h1>Rattan and Wicker</h1>
<p>No longer relegated to the front porch, rattan and wicker chairs, tables, and lighting add texture and detail.</p>
<h1>Free-Standing Tubs</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/nc_0_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590151326" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>There’s nothing like a luxurious soak in the tub. Homeowners remodeling the bathroom are adding or replacing a bathtub as part of the project. Sleek shapes and vintage-looking claw-foot tubs are both popular.<br> <br>Now kick that outdated fiddle fig to the curb and crack open a can of the paint color of the year. Whether it’s a subtle change or a complete make-over, make sure your home is on-trend for the decade ahead.</p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/New_NC_983e5b4f-a24a-4954-a12a-d041ef1252d6_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590589836" style="float: left;"></a><br> <a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/ButtonNew_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590586838" style="float: left;"></a><br>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/there-s-a-right-way-and-a-wrong-way-to-hang-art-on-the-wall</id>
    <published>2020-05-18T04:37:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-27T11:11:58-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/there-s-a-right-way-and-a-wrong-way-to-hang-art-on-the-wall"/>
    <title>There’s A Right Way - And A Wrong Way - To Hang Art On The Wall.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div>If only hanging art were as simple as pounding a nail into drywall.</div>
<div></div>
<div>In some cases, especially very lightweight artwork, it is.</div>
<div></div>
<div>In nearly all other cases, it’s not.</div><p><a class="read-more" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/there-s-a-right-way-and-a-wrong-way-to-hang-art-on-the-wall">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/header_1_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590592307" style="float: none;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<br>If only hanging art were as simple as pounding a nail into drywall.<br><br>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;">In some cases, especially very lightweight artwork, it is.<br><br>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">In nearly all other cases, it’s not.<br><br>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">Using the wrong type of hanger can send your artwork crashing to the ground.</div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<br>Ideally, you’ll hang your artwork - especially if it’s very heavy - on a stud. Studs are the vertical boards behind drywall. Typically, they are anywhere from 16 to 24 inches apart. <br><br>Most people find a stud by knocking on the wall. Drywall will sound hollow, and studs will sound more solid - which can be an exercise in frustration if you can’t hear a difference. <br><br>Here’s a tip. Studs are usually in the corner of a room, or around a light switch or window. Start tapping there to get a feel for it, then measure 16 inches away and tap to see if it feels the same.<br><br>When you’ve found the stud, drill a small pilot hole, then use a self-drilling screw.<br><br>Use one with a large, flat head and coarse threads that will bite into the stud. A screw length of 1-1/4 inch will suffice.<br><br>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;">Then, hang your art. You’re finished!<br><br>Wait, what? The stud isn’t where you want to hang your picture? No worries.<br><br>There are a variety of hangers designed to hold anything from a relatively lightweight picture to brackets and cabinets.</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Picture Hanger</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog4_9b275925-31e3-4f9a-b808-0e26efa5e6da_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590589232" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>For tools, all you’ll need is a small hammer. The configuration of a picture hanger’s angled nail and metal hook provides adequate support for most framed pictures. They come in different sizes for holding different weights. For larger frames, it is often advisable to use a pair of hangers.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;">Wall Anchor</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog3_4803cafa-5e01-4bd2-bd3c-1b55c8e726d8_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590589060" style="float: none;"></p>
<div>You’ll need a drill, a hammer, and a screwdriver. <br><br>Plastic wall anchors are sleeves into which a screw is tightened. Drill a hole, tap the anchor in until it is flush with the wall, then screw in a screw. <br><br>Tightening the screw causes the anchor to expand inside the wall. It’s essential to drill the proper size hole. Too small, the anchor won’t go in. Too large, the anchor has nothing to touch.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<h1 style="text-align: left;">
<em>“Molly”</em> Bolt</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog2_74f6e486-8a87-40f2-99b4-a79d1048c85c_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590588868" style="float: none;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">You’ll need a hammer and a screwdriver.<br><br>Hammer the sheathed expansion bolt (sometimes called a <em>“molly bolt”</em>) into the wall, then turn it clockwise with a screwdriver. When it will not turn any more, turn it counter-clockwise to “pull” its collar against the inside of the wall.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;">Toggle Bolt</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog1a_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590588638" style="float: none;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">You’ll need a drill, a hammer, and a screwdriver. <br><br>As with wall anchors, two-piece toggle bolt installation begins with drilling a pilot hole and then lightly tapping it into position. Suitable for more substantial jobs, toggle bolts have spring-activated <em>“wings”</em> that fold out once inside the hollow wall.<br><br>As you tighten the bolt with a screwdriver, the wings expand and draw against the wall.<br><br>Note: You have to create a pretty large hole to insert a toggle bolt, and once installed, removing the bolt from the wall will cause the wings to detach and fall behind the wall.<br><br>Now that you understand the differences between types of hanging hardware, you can hang your art with confidence. Happy decorating!</p>
<p><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/New_NC_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590585964" style="float: left;"></a><br><br><br></p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/ButtonNew_2048x2048.jpg?v=1590586838" style="float: left;"></a><br>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/freshen-your-walls-with-fresh-art</id>
    <published>2020-04-15T03:19:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-27T02:20:43-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/freshen-your-walls-with-fresh-art"/>
    <title>Spice Up Your Space In A Snap!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/nc_head1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1586935035" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>These days, you may be spending a lot of time staring at your walls. And you may be wondering how you can change the look of your rooms without a lot of time, effort or mess.</p>
<p>The answer is … art!</p>
<p>Professional decorators know that a new piece of art can bring unexpected color and movement to a room. It can make your space feel fresh and revived. It can put your existing furniture and other accessories into a whole new light.</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at how the pros change up rooms with art.</p>
<h1><strong>Artwork can add movement</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/x1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1587099531" style="float: none;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Lively, colorful artwork is a great contrast to the static objects in a room. Look for artwork that invites the eye to explore, such as abstract art pieces with lines and swirls of color. </p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Artwork can make colors pop</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/x3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1587104020" style="float: none;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Look around your room. You have probably decorated in a primary color, with some secondary colors for accents. But look for those small, illusive tertiary or subtle tones. Add some artwork containing those colors, and see how they jump to life throughout the room. </p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Artwork adds pow!</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/nc_head4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1586935723" style="float: none;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Is your room boring, beige, and non-descript? A bright artwork with vivid color adds excitement and can take a place from blah to bold.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Artwork can be subtle</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/nc_head5_1024x1024.jpg?v=1586935905" style="float: none;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Artwork doesn’t always need to be the focal point of a room. While artwork can influence a design or color palette and create bold statements, it can also be used in subtler ways to add sophistication.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Artwork can always change</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/nc_4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1587097530" style="float: none;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">If you hung a piece of art on the wall years ago and haven’t changed it, what’s stopping you? Move your existing art between rooms. Take older pieces down and hang newer ones. Take older pieces out of storage and put them in new places. </p>
<p style="text-align: left;">It doesn’t take a lot to change up the appearance of your rooms. Just add art!</p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/NC_F_83b1658c-07ed-4eec-90f8-656b3ab8c746_1024x1024.jpg?v=1586185906" style="float: left;"></a><br><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/preview-lightbox-NC_BlogButton_02a_1024x1024.jpg?v=1588735244" style="float: left;"></a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/how-to-store-art-correctly</id>
    <published>2020-03-30T01:53:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-27T02:19:54-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/how-to-store-art-correctly"/>
    <title>How To Store Art Correctly</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h6 style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Webp.net-compress-image_3_c8528588-c756-4c20-9c59-674a3fa88a50_1024x1024.jpg?v=1586706508" style="float: none;"></h6>
<p>Many don't realize how easy it is to store art wrong until they learn the hard way - by ruining their own. To help you avoid this we've created a handy guide to help you work out how best to store art if you're moving house or going away.</p>
<p>Ready to get clued up? Read on.</p>
<h1><strong>Is It Framed or Not?</strong></h1>
<p>Framed and non-framed art require different processes for correct storage...</p>
<p><strong>Framed Art:</strong> Use a storage blanket or sheet of bubble wrap and wrap around the artwork. Then seal using packing tape. Now, grab a few pieces of hardboard to pad the front and the back, then seal them together too.</p>
<p><strong>Unframed Art:</strong> Use silicone release paper to cover the front, then wrap with glassine paper. Use hardboard to pad the front and the back, then wrap in bubble wrap or a blanket. Secure it all together with packing tape.</p>
<h1><strong>Now for the dos and don'ts of proper storage...</strong></h1>
<h6 style="text-align: left;">
<img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/dreamstime_1024x1024.jpg?v=1586705896" style="float: none;">                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             <strong>Credit: dreamstime</strong>
</h6>
<h2><strong>Do know the temperature conditions.</strong></h2>
<p>Sudden changes in temperature are dangerous to art because it can make the canvas slacken, stretch, or tighten. These movements cause the paint to flake off over time.</p>
<p>Another factor to watch out for is humidity, which encourages the growth of mold. The ideal conditions to aim for are 70 degrees Fahrenheit and 55% humidity.</p>
<h6 style="text-align: right;"></h6>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Don't touch with bare hands</strong></h2>
<p>You should use gloves when packing because the oils on your skin can react with the paints and cause discoloration. The best option when it comes to gloves are white ones, as they're least likely to stain your art.</p>
<h2><strong>Do use padding</strong></h2>
<p>You should always aim to store your artworks separately, not on top of each other or side by side. But sometimes this can't be avoided. In these cases, make sure you use a painting rack or padding to separate them.</p>
<h6 style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Webp.net-compress-image_8_1024x1024.jpg?v=1586776106" style="float: none;"></h6>
<h2><strong>Do air your paintings</strong></h2>
<p>If you intend to store your paintings for a long time it's essential to air them occasionally. This prevents humidity buildup, which in turn, prevents potential molding.</p>
<h2><strong>Don't store in attics or basements</strong></h2>
<p>Never store your artworks in these places. The damp or dry conditions of the loft or the cellar are perfect places for damage to your art to occur. If you have to, then try to keep humidity to a low and temperatures constant.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Avoid direct sunlight</strong></h2>
<p>Always keep your paintings away from direct sunlight. That's because the UV rays from the sun can cause discoloration and fading.</p>
<p>If you're about to store your art, we hope these tips were helpful. Follow them closely to avoid any damage.</p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/NC_F_83b1658c-07ed-4eec-90f8-656b3ab8c746_1024x1024.jpg?v=1586185906" style="float: left;"></a><br><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/preview-lightbox-NC_BlogButton_02a_1024x1024.jpg?v=1588735244" style="float: left;"></a><br>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/picking-picture-perfect-wall-art</id>
    <published>2020-03-06T10:11:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-27T02:19:09-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/picking-picture-perfect-wall-art"/>
    <title>Picking Picture-Perfect Wall Art</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>﻿<img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Wall_decoration_1024x1024.jpg?v=1584033428" style="float: none;"></strong></p>
<p>A room isn’t finished until the art is on the walls. Art adds color, personality, and pizzazz. It’s what makes a room feel finished.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the sight of bare walls can drive us to purchase the first thing we see. And probably regret it.</p>
<p>Before you make an impulsive purchase, take a look at our tips for choosing perfect wall art for every room of your home.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/childrens-for-girls-3368014_1920_59623281-4597-4c75-8455-109f6ffcd7aa_1024x1024.jpg?v=1583522690" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1><strong>What’s the room’s personality?</strong></h1>
<p>Is the space high-energy with lots of activity, such as a family room or playroom?</p>
<p>Consider colorful prints or wall art with lively colors and abstract patterns.</p>
<p>Bedrooms and bathrooms are rooms that evoke a sense of peace and calm.</p>
<p>In these spaces, dreamy, soothing watercolors, or simple monochromatic photographs can enhance relaxation.</p>
<p>Offices and kitchens are great places for colorful conversation pieces such as posters and graphic prints.</p>
<p>And formal living rooms and dining rooms are perfect places for stately oil paintings.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/wall_art_1024x1024.jpg?v=1583521664" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1><strong>Take inventory</strong></h1>
<p>You may have a painting, print, or photograph that you love. If so, use it as the foundation, then add new art and decor to complement your existing artwork.</p>
<p>Don’t forget to take into consideration other forms of wall art, too, such as sculpture, plates, textiles, baskets, mirrors, and framed collections.</p>
<p>You may be surprised by what you have!</p>
<h1><strong>Determine the focal point</strong></h1>
<p>Do you want the wall art to be the focal point of the room? Or do you want it to be subtle and understated and complement your furnishings?</p>
<p>If you want all eyes on your art, use a neutral color scheme throughout the room.</p>
<p>Another trick is to arrange the room’s furnishings so that it leads the eye through the room. If the bed is the first thing you see in the bedroom, hang wall art above it.</p>
<p>Another way to make artwork the focal point of the room is to choose a unique, one-of-a-kind piece.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Webp.net-compress-image_12_1024x1024.jpg?v=1584203539" alt=""></p>
<h1><strong>Use eye-level placement</strong></h1>
<p>As a general rule, display wall art so that the center of the piece or collection hangs at eye level. Here’s a guide that art galleries around the world use: Display the artwork’s <em>center</em> 57 inches from the floor.</p>
<p>But there are exceptions to every rule. In dining rooms or home offices, consider hanging wall art a little lower since you will be sitting down.</p>
<p>For clusters of smaller works, such as a collection of watercolors or framed photographs, keep spacing to less than six inches between each piece.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/im3rd-media-pw4lFeS2x38-unsplash_1024x1024.jpg?v=1583783351" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1><strong>Feel free to experiment</strong></h1>
<p>Unsure of how your wall art grouping will look? Lay it on the floor and arrange and rearrange until you’re satisfied.</p>
<p>Another trick is to use paper templates and painter’s tape to experiment with different placement and spacing.</p>
<h1><strong>Above all else, go with your intuition</strong></h1>
<p>When it comes to artwork, purchase pieces that you love, that you want to see every day, and that reflect your style.</p>
<p>After all, it’s your room and your art!</p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/best-sellers-1"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Blog_1_2d939d2a-d472-4783-8edc-70f0ea425ed0_1024x1024.jpg?v=1583940724" style="float: left;"></a><br><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/preview-lightbox-NC_BlogButton_02a_1024x1024.jpg?v=1588735244" style="float: left;"></a><br>
<div></div>
<div></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/how-to-keep-your-canvas-looking-10-10</id>
    <published>2020-03-05T14:46:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-27T02:18:11-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/how-to-keep-your-canvas-looking-10-10"/>
    <title>How to Keep Your Canvas Looking 10/10</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>So, you've invested in a b-e-a-utiful canvas that breathes new life into your home and adds a ton of character.</p>
<p>You want it to stay looking great, but over time canvases can degrade if not looked after properly.</p>
<p>To keep it looking tip-top, cleaning is essential.</p>
<p>Good canvas upkeep isn't exactly common knowledge, but thankfully it's easy to learn.</p>
<p>Here are our best tips for keeping your canvas looking 10/10.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/how-to-keep-your-canvas-looking-10-10">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/1_41660ba6-1e57-4022-8866-87f225453261_1024x1024.jpg?v=1590559826" style="float: none;"></div>
<br>
<p>So, you've invested in a b-e-a-utiful canvas that breathes new life into your home and adds a ton of character.</p>
<p>You want it to stay looking great, but over time canvases can degrade if not looked after properly.</p>
<p>To keep it looking tip-top, cleaning is essential.</p>
<p>Good canvas upkeep isn't exactly common knowledge, but thankfully it's easy to learn.</p>
<p>Here are our best tips for keeping your canvas looking 10/10.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/brown-wooden-dining-set-in-dining-room-2029673_1024x1024.jpg?v=1583440340" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1><strong>Dust Softly </strong></h1>
<p>To keep your canvas clean you're gonna have to learn to dust it.</p>
<p>Be cautious, however, because scrubbing too vigorously is a good way to ruin it.</p>
<p>Instead, gently run a damp cloth over it.</p>
<p>Make sure it's a soft cloth made of cotton or microfiber, and remember to only spray water onto the cloth, not directly onto the canvas.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/sidekix-media-1vMz2_MclrM-unsplash_1024x1024.jpg?v=1583490731" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1><strong>Avoid Chemicals</strong></h1>
<p>Dusting with water and a cloth will usually be enough to get your canvas clean.</p>
<p>If however, there's a more serious stain to be dealt with, you may need something more.</p>
<p>If you're reaching for household cleaners or harsh chemicals though, be careful. These will usually cause even more damage.</p>
<p>When encountering stubborn stains it's better to enlist a specialist than attempt to clean it yourself.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/NC3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1583486535" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1><strong>Hang it right</strong></h1>
<p>When it comes to hanging your prints, there are a few areas you want to avoid.</p>
<p>Hanging your canvas in a humid location like a small bathroom or a room with bad air circulation is a definite no-no.</p>
<p>It's okay to display your art outside briefly, but it's not a viable option in the long term.</p>
<p>Weather conditions like rain or even direct sunlight can easily ruin your canvas.</p>
<p>Try to find a place in the house with low humidity and minimal variations in temperature.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/NC2_1024x1024.jpg?v=1583486440" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1><strong>Store It Right</strong></h1>
<p>Even in storage, your canvases can deteriorate.</p>
<p>Avoid this by making sure you wrap the canvas in bubble-wrap or acid-free craft paper.</p>
<p>This protects it from exposure and reduces the chances of dust accumulating.</p>
<p>No one wants to see their canvas deteriorate.</p>
<p>Thankfully, with these simple tips you can make sure that your canvas continues to brighten your home for years to come.</p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/NC_F_1024x1024.jpg?v=1583438024" style="float: left;"></a><br><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/preview-lightbox-NC_BlogButton_02a_1024x1024.jpg?v=1588735244" style="float: left;"></a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/five-secrets-for-winning-color-combos</id>
    <published>2020-02-19T07:24:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-07T23:24:59-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/five-secrets-for-winning-color-combos"/>
    <title>Five Secrets For Winning Color Combos</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>You’d think that an awesome piece of art would look good anywhere, but trust us. That's not the case. Pairing your art with your walls ain't easy, but it's very, very important. Here are five tips for choosing the perfect combination of art and wall color.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/five-secrets-for-winning-color-combos">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Webp.net-compress-image_3_3d4a860b-b860-4a96-b3e3-57fac81dfbc1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1582366702" alt=""></p>
<p>You’d think that an awesome piece of art would look good anywhere, but trust us. That's not the case.</p>
<p>Pairing your art with your walls ain't easy, but it's very, very important.</p>
<p>Here are five tips for choosing the perfect combination of art and wall color.</p>
<h1><strong>Don’t Always Go for The Obvious Choice. </strong></h1>
<p>Your art and your walls should match, right? </p>
<p>Well, not always. Often the predominant color in your art isn’t the one that will be most appealing.</p>
<p>It’s always worth looking beyond your first impression.</p>
<p>Always give a few different colors that <em>weren’t</em> your first choice a whirl before committing.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Webp.net-compress-image_2_1024x1024.jpg?v=1582365453" alt=""></p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Work with color slivers</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;">Pick out one of the minor colors in your artwork to paint the walls.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">This way you'll get a great contrast while still tying both elements together through use of a common color.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Webp.net-compress-image_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1582365394" alt=""></p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Think about gradients</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;">One way of coordinating art with colors easier gradients. A gradient is the same color, but with different saturation or intensity.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">For example, if your artwork has bright turquoise in it, paint the walls a lighter shade of turquoise.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/1A_1024x1024.jpg?v=1582213328" alt=""></p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Be cautious with your paintbrush</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;">Remember, the color you choose determines what else will work with your room and what just won’t.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">A bold, daring color like hot pink will limit your options for the future.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Therefore, it’s a good idea to stick to safer colors unless you carry your bold choice throughout the rest of your furnishings and accessories.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/ezgif.com-webp-to-jpg_f4680af2-4e21-4423-939f-98a15cd6a21e_1024x1024.jpg?v=1582367241" alt=""></p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Find winning color combinations</strong></h1>
<p>Still unsure? That's OK. Thankfully, the internet can help.</p>
<p>Find examples of an online, interactive color wheel, which demonstrates color theory.</p>
<p>Used by many designers, color theory is a practical combination o fart an science that's used to determine what colors look good together.</p>
<p>One last tip: Splurge on those little jars of paint samples, which will help you find your winning combination.</p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Blog_foot_1024x1024.jpg?v=1582114859" style="float: left;"></a><br><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/preview-lightbox-NC_BlogButton_02a_1024x1024.jpg?v=1588735244" style="float: left;"></a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/4-unarguable-reasons-why-you-just-gotta-have-wall-art</id>
    <published>2020-02-13T02:33:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-20T01:07:19-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/4-unarguable-reasons-why-you-just-gotta-have-wall-art"/>
    <title>4 Unarguable Reasons Why You Just GOTTA Have Wall Art</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Your empty walls are the blank canvases that can be used to express yourself. And there are even more reasons why you should go ahead and add art to your walls. Here are 4 reasons why you gotta get some things on those walls.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/4-unarguable-reasons-why-you-just-gotta-have-wall-art">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Webp.net-compress-image_3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1581599737" style="float: none;"></p>
<div style="text-align: left;">No matter how into <i>"</i><em>minimalism"</em> you are, there’s no denying it — bare walls suck.</div>
<div style="text-align: left;">Your empty walls are the blank canvases that can be used to express yourself. And there are even more reasons why you should go ahead and add art to your walls.</div>
<div style="text-align: left;">Sure, we might be a little biased (we’re all about wall art), but here are 4 reasons why you gotta get some things on those walls.</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/nc_h1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1581594365" style="float: none;"></h1>
<h1>Art Helps You Pick a Color Palette</h1>
<p>Choosing a color palette for a room is daunting, no doubt. With literally thousands of color combinations, how are you supposed to pick just ONE?!</p>
<p>Fear not, chronically indecisive interior designers, because wall art can help.</p>
<p>Put the paint swatches down and focus on finding great pieces for your walls instead.</p>
<p>Once you’ve found a painting you love, use its dominant color few of the secondary shades to build a your color theme for the room.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/nc_h2_1024x1024.jpg?v=1581594467" style="float: none;"></h1>
<h1>Art Creates a Focal Point</h1>
<p>Trust us, every room needs a bold focal point that draws the eye. A brave piece of art hanging proudly above your bed or fireplace makes a bold statement.</p>
<p>The most important consideration is size, and as they say, size matters. Too small and your piece will be dwarfed by its surroundings.</p>
<p>Too big and it will dwarf everything else!</p>
<p>Make sure to measure your wall space and any furniture, if necessary, and be armed with this info before you make your purchase.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/h5_1024x1024.jpg?v=1581491424" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1>Gives Adds Textures</h1>
<p>Wall art gives you loads of great options for mixing up your textures. Of course, you might just want to stick with something like a 2-dimensional piece or similar.</p>
<p>But in addition to paintings and prints, you could mix things up by introducing sculptures or shadow boxes that will add depth to your room.</p>
<p>It doesn’t stop there either. Go even further and introduce mixed media like screens or digital art . . . It is 2020 after all.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/nc_h4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1581594673" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1>Wall Art <em>"Finishes"</em> A Room</h1>
<p>Remember the last time you moved? Your new home probably didn’t feel like home until the art was hung on the walls.</p>
<p>Bare walls are just as much as a signature of an incomplete room as walls bursting with art are the opposite.</p>
<p>It’s the finishing element that ties a space together and gives it a sense of completion.</p>
<p>So take a look at your walls. Seem empty? Just add art!</p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/FootNC_1024x1024.jpg?v=1588910332" style="float: left;"></a><br><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/FootNC2_1024x1024.jpg?v=1588910397" style="float: left;"></a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/3-rules-to-hang-your-art-like-a-pro</id>
    <published>2020-01-21T07:44:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-07T23:30:56-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/3-rules-to-hang-your-art-like-a-pro"/>
    <title>3 Rules To Hang Your Art Like A Pro</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Hanging a picture can be an agonizing process of trial and error. It doesn’t matter how beautiful your artwork looks if it’s not hung on the wall properly. Here are our tips for displaying your artwork beautifully.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/3-rules-to-hang-your-art-like-a-pro">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/h1_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1579613813" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Maybe you were born with an eye for design, color, and layout. Perhaps you’re one of those people who can simply drive a nail into the wall and hang a picture that’s in perfect alignment.</p>
<p>Good for you.</p>
<p>But for the rest of us, hanging a picture can be an agonizing process of trial and error that turns walls into Swiss cheese.</p>
<p>It doesn’t matter how beautiful your artwork looks if it’s not hung on the wall properly. Here are our tips for displaying your artwork beautifully.</p>
<h1><strong><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/image2_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1579517002"></strong></h1>
<h1><strong>Tip #1: Hang at Eye Level</strong></h1>
<p>You’ve probably heard that artwork should be hung at eye-level. But whose eye-level? Someone who is 5’2”…  or 6’7”?</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Here’s a rule that art galleries around the world use: Always display the artwork’s <em>center</em> 57 inches from the floor. Not the ceiling. The floor.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Repeat: The center of the piece. Not the top edge. Never <em>“eyeball”</em> or guestimate. A metal measuring tape is essential, especially if you are hanging several pieces in a grouping.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Of course, there are exceptions to every rule.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Image_3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1579517536" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Tip #2: Don’t Hang at Eye Level</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;">Here’s an exception to the 57-inch rule: When hanging artwork above furniture, such as a sofa or bed, the bottom of the frame should be between six to eight inches above the top of the furniture.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Does this place the center of the artwork higher than 57 inches? It’s OK.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/image_2_1024x1024.jpg?v=1579517332" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Tip #3: Keep Things in Proportion</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;">Of course, when hanging art above larger pieces of furniture, it should be in proportion.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">An individual piece or layout of multiple pieces that are about a third of the furniture’s size is the general rule of thumb. Otherwise, the artwork will appear too small or too large.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And speaking of multiple pieces, treat them as one large piece of art.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p><strong><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/image_5_1024x1024.jpg?v=1579521856"></strong></p>
<h1><strong>Tip #4: Managing Multiples</strong></h1>
<p>Lay your artwork out on the floor in your desired pattern. This makes it easy to play with their arrangement before you pound a bunch of nails into the wall.</p>
<p>No floor space? No problem!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Cut kraft paper into templates that match the size of the art and tape them to the wall with painter’s tape. Write a description of the piece (“<em>Susan’s baby picture,” “sunflowers in vase”)</em> on the paper for reference.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">This will give you a nice visual as to how your arrangement will look before hanging. Then, leave the templates in place as you hammer and hang each item.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And don’t forget the 57-inch rule: Hanging multiple works around the 57-inch focal point will make the entire group appear balanced.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">One more thing: When spacing between pieces, the ideal width is 3 to 6 inches.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Follow these four easy tips when hanging art, and your artwork will look picture perfect.</p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/b1_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1579533502" style="float: left;"></a><br><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/preview-lightbox-NC_BlogButton_02a_1024x1024.jpg?v=1588735244" style="float: left;"></a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/7-common-mistakes-people-make-when-hanging-art</id>
    <published>2020-01-12T08:25:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-07T23:15:24-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/7-common-mistakes-people-make-when-hanging-art"/>
    <title>7 Common Mistakes People Make When Hanging Art</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>From positioning, sizing, to how it fits with the rest of your room – there’s a lot that can go wrong. We are here to walk you through some of the most common mistakes we see people making.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/7-common-mistakes-people-make-when-hanging-art">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Header_Final_1024x1024.jpg?v=1578665017" alt=""></p>
<p>There’s more to displaying art than simply fixing it to your wall.</p>
<p>In fact, if you want to get the most out of your artistic gems, you’ve gotta think about a whole range of factors when decorating. </p>
<p>From positioning, sizing, to how it fits with the rest of your room – there’s a lot that can go wrong.</p>
<p>But never fear, cos we at NicheCanvas are here to walk you through some of the most common mistakes we see people making.</p>
<p>Read on to protect yourself against making these blunders...</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/p3_FInal_1024x1024.jpg?v=1579073661" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1><strong>1. Trying To Fill Up Every Wall In The House </strong></h1>
<p>We get it. For art lovers, restricting yourself to just a few pieces can seem impossible.</p>
<p>But it's quality, not quantity, that creates amazing spaces.</p>
<p>Don’t drown your room in painting upon painting. Instead, be selective with your choices.</p>
<p>More art doesn’t automatically mean more beauty.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Keeping_Art_Too_High_1024x1024.jpg?v=1578665236" alt=""></p>
<h1><strong>2. Keeping Art Too High</strong></h1>
<p>Unless you’re trying to cater to the extremely tall, hanging your art in the lofty reaches of your walls is a big no-no.</p>
<p>This is one of the most common mistakes we see, but thankfully it’s easy to fix.</p>
<p>If you’re looking for a simple way to give your décor a boost, take a walk through your home and evaluate your art's positioning.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/samey_1024x1024.jpg?v=1578667446" alt=""></p>
<h1><strong>3. Your Art Is Too Samey </strong></h1>
<p>It’s your home, so you’ve got the freedom to go wild – use it!</p>
<p>What we’re saying is, don’t stick to one style of art and let your home décor become boring.</p>
<p>Mix it up. Swap out framed art for canvases, tapestries, quilts, or whatever weird and wonderful ornaments deserve to adorn your wall.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Messy_Wall_Collages_1024x1024.jpg?v=1578665323" alt=""></p>
<h1><strong>4. Messy Wall Collages  </strong></h1>
<p>Face it, no one can just freestyle a wall collage and have it come out looking perfect - unless they’re <em>extremely</em> lucky.</p>
<p>Creating a great wall collage takes some planning.</p>
<p>Before you start boring holes in your walls, make sure you know how your collage is likely to take shape, then you can give yourself the best chance of success.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Using_The_Wrong_Sizes_1024x1024.jpg?v=1578665483" alt=""></p>
<h1><strong>5. Using The Wrong Sizes </strong></h1>
<p>There are few things more jarring for an interior designer than seeing a wall hanging that very clearly doesn’t match the size of the room.</p>
<p>Going too big or too small in a room that cries out for something different is common, but it’s easily fixed. </p>
<p>For example, when something’s too small, you can remedy it by reframing with a larger mat or thicker frame.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Matching_Everything_1024x1024.jpg?v=1578665294" alt=""></p>
<h1><strong>6. Matching Everything</strong></h1>
<p>Clever home design isn’t all about uniformity. In fact, sometimes the best homes are those that surprise you at every turn.</p>
<p>Don’t confine yourself to perfectly matching colors. You should experiment with your palette and let your pieces stand out. </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/Final_4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1579073793" style="float: none;"></p>
<h1><strong>7. Not hanging them properly. </strong></h1>
<p>This one is simple – but you’d be surprised how common it is! Hang your art properly.</p>
<p>You want your pictures securely fixed so that they aren’t constantly being knocked off-kilter every time a strong breeze blows through the door.</p>
<p>And that's it!</p>
<p>We hope you enjoyed the tips and will avoid falling into these deadly decoration disasters – your home (and guests) will thank you for it!</p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/blog_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1579075166" style="float: left;"></a><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><br><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/preview-lightbox-NC_BlogButton_02a_1024x1024.jpg?v=1588735244" style="float: left;"></a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/simple-stunning-xmas-light-tips</id>
    <published>2019-12-11T21:12:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-07T23:51:42-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/simple-stunning-xmas-light-tips"/>
    <title>💡 Simple, Stunning Xmas Light Tips To Transform Your Home</title>
    <author>
      <name>Antony Breton</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>It doesn’t matter whether you prefer the warmth of steady-glowing lights or the excitement of flashing and dashing lights... Now you can decorate for the holidays any way and anywhere you wish!</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://nichecanvas.com/blogs/artlove/simple-stunning-xmas-light-tips">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/1_1024x1024.jpeg?v=1576123241" alt=""></div>
<div>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><br>Did you know that Holidays lights have been around since before electricity?</p>
<p>How?</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>Well, back in those dark pre-electrical days, Christmas trees were adorned with tiny, flickering candles.</span><br><span> </span><br><span>Thankfully, they didn’t stay lit long and a bucket of water was always close by.</span></p>
<p><span><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/4_1024x1024.jpeg?v=1576123429" alt=""></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>Then, came those big painted light bulbs. They too, burned hot and were a fire hazard, but were much safer than candles.<br> <br>Today we have much safer alternatives that emit little, if no heat.<br> <br>And thanks to batteries and solar-charging, we can put lights practically anywhere!</span></p>
<p><span><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/3_1024x1024.jpeg?v=1576123482" alt=""></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>Twinkle lights around a mirror for twice the brightness.</span></p>
<p><span><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/5_1024x1024.jpeg?v=1576123679" alt=""></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>Snowflake-shaped lights cascading from the ceiling create a wintry wonderland.</span></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/2_1024x1024.jpeg?v=1576123300" alt=""></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>No tree? No problem! Just use some sturdy tape and your imagination!</span></p>
<p><span><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/xmaslights_1024x1024.jpeg?v=1576123588" alt=""></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Some battery-operated lights, a few ornaments and a wide-mouth jar equal instant holiday cheer.<br> <br>It doesn’t matter whether you prefer the warmth of steady-glowing lights or the excitement of flashing and dashing lights...</p>
<p>Now you can decorate for the holidays any way and anywhere you wish!</p>
<p style="float: left;"><a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/trending-products-2_1024x1024.jpg?v=1576484929" style="float: left;"></a></p>
<a href="https://nichecanvas.com/collections/premium-collection"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2012/8501/files/preview-lightbox-NC_BlogButton_02a_1024x1024.jpg?v=1588735244" style="float: left;"></a>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
